<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analysis on Bram Steensma</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/data-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Analysis on Bram Steensma</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/data-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When Anonymous Isn&#39;t Really Anonymous: A Data Ethics Crisis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-anonymous-isnt-really-anonymous/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/when-anonymous-isnt-really-anonymous/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Organizations depend on course feedback surveys to improve their training programs. This process seems straightforward: students take an “anonymous” survey, management reviews the results, and courses are updated based on feedback. But what happens when the promise of anonymity is undermined by the survey’s own design?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s examine a real-world scenario. In this organization, survey participants are assured their responses will remain anonymous. Yet, the structure of the survey reveals fundamental flaws that dissolve this promise. The implications reach beyond poor design—they erode trust, challenge consent, create data governance concerns, and put pressure on the ethical responsibilities of data professionals.&#xA;This isn’t just a theoretical dilemma; it’s the type of ethical puzzle data analysts regularly face, where technical systems can quietly clash with core ethical principles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to My Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/welcome-to-my-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/welcome-to-my-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to My Blog&#xA;I’m glad you’re here. This website marks an exciting new chapter for me as I transition from over a decade in IT support and customer service into the world of data analysis and AI. I recently started the Data Analysis and AI Specialist program at Eastern College, and one of our first projects was to build a personal website using Hugo.&#xA;I decided to build mine using the CareerCanvas theme by Felipe Cordero to give it a polished, professional feel that reflects where I’m headed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
